export const final_mdsp_coaching_phase_2 = [
  {
    choices: ["a make the outside diameter concentric with the bore", "none of the above", "make the sides of wheel parallel", "equalize the weight in every portion of the wheel"],
    correctAnswer: "equalize the weight in every portion of the wheel",
    question: "Balancing of grinding wheel is done to:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["above center", "off center ", "at the center", "below the center"],
    correctAnswer: "at the center",
    question: "When facing off a piece of material in the lathe chuck the bit must be set",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium duty", "none of the above", "heavy duty", "light duty"],
    correctAnswer: "heavy duty",
    question: "Planer type milling machine is built up for work of:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "10 degree ", "70 degree", "80 degree"],
    correctAnswer: "10 degree ",
    question: "If the clearance of a cutting edge is 5 degrees, the lip (wedge) angle in 75 degree the rake angle will be,",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "screw thread micrometer", "combi micrometer", "inside micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "inside micrometer",
    question: "Which micrometer is available with extension rods:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above ", "lower speed", "higher speed", "average speed"],
    correctAnswer: "higher speed",
    question: "In a hydraulic driven shaper the metal is removed at:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["wheel is hard", "grain size is too fine", "wheel speed is too fast", "A and B both"],
    correctAnswer: "A and B both",
    question: "One of the cause of grinding wheel glazing is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["&amp;amp;#39;Go&amp;amp;#39; Size", "none of the above", "&amp;amp;#39;Not Go&amp;amp;#39; Size", "A and B both"],
    correctAnswer: "&amp;amp;#39;Not Go&amp;amp;#39; Size",
    question: "In case of a limit plug gauge which size will not enter into the hole:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["A and B both", "neither A and B", "same direction", "opposite direction"],
    correctAnswer: "opposite direction",
    question: "In internal cylindrical grinding the grinding wheel and the work rotate in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["to control the size", "all of the above", "to finish the job to a fine degree of accuracy", "to get high quality of surface teeth"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "Lapping is done",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium", "soft", "none of the above", "hard"],
    correctAnswer: "medium",
    question: "As per Indian standard &amp;amp;#39;M&amp;amp;#39; grade wheel comes under the group:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["during up cut milling with a straight tooth cutter", "during face milling with a straight tooth cutter", "during down cut milling with a straight tooth cutter", "while using spiral tooth cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "during up cut milling with a straight tooth cutter",
    question: "Mark the milling method during which the formation of chatter marks is very likely.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["45°", "47.5°", "60°", "55°"],
    correctAnswer: "47.5°",
    question: "The angle of B.A. screw thread is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["plain milling cutter", "end mill cutter", "all of the above", "form relieve cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "form relieve cutter",
    question: "For gear cutting which cutter is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["straight", "right hand", "left hand", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "left hand",
    question: "Generally spiral fluted reamer has spirals of:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["column", "spindle", "table", "arbor"],
    correctAnswer: "arbor",
    question: "The over arm of a milling machine is used to support:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["in &amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; form", "parallel to each other", "A and B both", "neither A nor B"],
    correctAnswer: "in &amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; form",
    question: "The jaws of a leg vice are opened:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["on face plate", "in three jaw chuck", "on lathe mandrel", "between centers"],
    correctAnswer: "on lathe mandrel",
    question: "When outside diameter of a job is turned in relation to the internal hole, the job should be held:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the beginning of return stroke", "the middle of return stroke", "the beginning of cutting stroke", "the end of return stroke"],
    correctAnswer: "the end of return stroke",
    question: "The feed in the shaper takes place at:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["high carbon steel", "H.S.S.", "lead", "wood"],
    correctAnswer: "wood",
    question: "The clamping block to be used in a slotter to support the end of the strap is made of",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "changing its inclination", "changing the convexity of the cutting angle", "changing its weight"],
    correctAnswer: "changing its inclination",
    question: "In case of a flat scraper, the depth of the cut is verified by:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["hydraulic mechanism", "slotter link and gear mechanism", "whitworth mechanism", "slotter dist mechanism"],
    correctAnswer: "whitworth mechanism",
    question: "Which of the following quick return mechanism is most widely used in most of the slotters:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the blade have very sharp teeth", "the space is not sufficient to play the new blade in the old cut", "none of the above", "the blade is very costly"],
    correctAnswer: "the space is not sufficient to play the new blade in the old cut",
    question: "A new hacksaw blade should not be used in old cut because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["away from the center of crank disc", "at the center of crank", "none of the above", "towards the center of crank disc"],
    correctAnswer: "away from the center of crank disc",
    question: "Amount of automatic feed in shaper is increased by taking the crank pin:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["kind of bond", "kind of abrasive", "grain size", "structure"],
    correctAnswer: "structure",
    question: "A grinding wheel is marked as 51A 46L 5V 23, out of these 5 means:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["mm/stroke", "mm/revolution", "meter/minute", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "mm/stroke",
    question: "In a shaper the feed (metric) is usually expressed in:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it is specially designed by experts", "none of the above ", "it is easy for production", "it accomodates the handle and a wedge for preventing it from flying off"],
    correctAnswer: "it accomodates the handle and a wedge for preventing it from flying off",
    question: "The eye hole of a hammer head is made in oval shape and taper towards centre because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "chamois leather or lenen cloth", "brush", "cotton waste"],
    correctAnswer: "chamois leather or lenen cloth",
    question: "Which of the following is used to clean the gauge blocks before and after use:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["5 mm", "15 mm", "25 mm", "50 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "15 mm",
    question: "Shaper tool bit should not extend in tool holder beyond:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["semi-soft", "semi-hard", "hard", "soft"],
    correctAnswer: "hard",
    question: "The jaw of a standard vise is",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["at the end of return motion", "after each forward stroke", "during the cutting motion", "after each double stroke"],
    correctAnswer: "after each double stroke",
    question: "Where does the speed motion takes place in slotting machine?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cast steel", "tool steel", "high speed steel", "closed grain cast iron"],
    correctAnswer: "closed grain cast iron",
    question: "Angle plate is made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["62 HRC", "72 HRC", "45 HRC", "52 HRC"],
    correctAnswer: "62 HRC",
    question: "The approximate hardness of HSS end mill cutter is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["a cam", "an eccentric", "A and C", "a round stock"],
    correctAnswer: "A and C",
    question: "A universal chuck cannot be used to cut",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["actual and nominal", "minimum and maximum", "nominal and lower limit", "nominal and upper limit"],
    correctAnswer: "minimum and maximum",
    question: "Limit gauge is made to the ________ sizes of the work to be measured:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: [" ", "prevent the loading of wheel", "all of the above", "reduce the friction between the wheel face and the job"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "Grinding fluids are used to:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "screw thread micrometer", "digit micrometer", "depth micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "depth micrometer",
    question: "Which micrometer has no anvil:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["side milling cutters", "face milling cutters", "form cutters", "plain milling cutters"],
    correctAnswer: "side milling cutters",
    question: "The straddle milling is done by means of two:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["square", "knuckle", "acme", "buttress"],
    correctAnswer: "square",
    question: "In which screw thread the side = width of flat = width space = 0.5p",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["relief", "flutes", "threads", "diameter"],
    correctAnswer: "flutes",
    question: "Taps are resharpened by grindings:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["T = N/20", "T = 40/N", "T = 20/N", "T= N/40"],
    correctAnswer: "T = 40/N",
    question: "The formula to find out the number of turn of the crank for simple indexing is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["A and B both", "neither A and B", "upper limit of the shaft", "lower limit of the shaft"],
    correctAnswer: "A and B both",
    question: "&amp;amp;#39;Go&amp;amp;#39; Limit is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["materials of the slotter tool", "finish required", "material to be used", "all of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "In a slotter the cutting speed depends upon:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium duty", "none of the above", "light duty", "heavy duty"],
    correctAnswer: "heavy duty",
    question: "Planer type milling machine is built up for _____ work of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["tungsten", "nickel", "vanadium", "chromium"],
    correctAnswer: "tungsten",
    question: "Main alloying element in H.S.S. is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["18% Chromium and 8% Nickel", "18% Nickel and 8% Chromium", "18% Chromium and 8% Cobalt", "18% Tungsten and 8% Chromium"],
    correctAnswer: "18% Chromium and 8% Nickel",
    question: "&amp;amp;#39;18 - 8&amp;amp;#39; stainless steel means:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["10 mm", "100 mm", "1 mm", "4 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "100 mm",
    question: "If rpm = 200, feed per revolution = 0.05mm, then feed per minute will be:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["semi-circular milling cutter", "shell end mill", "plain milling cutter", "side milling cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "shell end mill",
    question: "Mark the cutter which works simultaneously with up cut and down cut process:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["corrundum", "emery", "silicon carbide", "aluminum carbide"],
    correctAnswer: "silicon carbide",
    question: "For grinding materials having low tensile strength which abrasive is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["4°", "6°", "1°", "2°"],
    correctAnswer: "1°",
    question: "In a standard dividing head 3 holes in 27 holes circles will be:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["3:1", "3:2", "2:3", "1:3"],
    correctAnswer: "3:2",
    question: "The standard ratio of cutting to return stroke in shaper is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "dial test indicator", "vernier caliper", "tube micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "dial test indicator",
    question: "Concentricity of a outside diameter can be checked by:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["two housing", "one housing", "one table", "two tables"],
    correctAnswer: "two tables",
    question: "Divided table planer has:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["clamping arrangement", "tool guiding element", "all of the above ", "manufacturing conditions"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above ",
    question: "Successful designing of jigs and fixtures depend upon:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["thread plug gauge", "thread ring gauge", "plug gauge", "ring gauge"],
    correctAnswer: "thread plug gauge",
    question: "Which gauge is used to check the internal threads:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["one", "none of the above", "three or more", "two"],
    correctAnswer: "three or more",
    question: "In a slotter the table gets ______ different feeds:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["&amp;amp;#39;B&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;R&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;E&amp;amp;#39;"],
    correctAnswer: "&amp;amp;#39;B&amp;amp;#39;",
    question: "The symbol conventionally used for resinoid bond is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["speed is too fast", "speed is too low", "material cannot be done", "material is too hard"],
    correctAnswer: "speed is too fast",
    question: "When lathe tool bit burns, it means that the",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the job will be out of round", "the job will be thrown out", "the job will not rotate", "the job will be oversized"],
    correctAnswer: "the job will be out of round",
    question: "What happens if the job is loosely fitted between centers in cylindrical grindings:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cast iron", "tool steel", "brass", "mild steel"],
    correctAnswer: "tool steel",
    question: "Jig bushings are generally made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["form", "round nose", "&amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; shaped", "gooseneck"],
    correctAnswer: "form",
    question: "For cutting gear teeth in a shaper, the ______ tool is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["45° only", "90° only", "any angle between 0° - 108", "90° and 45°"],
    correctAnswer: "90° and 45°",
    question: "The square head of a combination set is used for markings or checking the angles",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["horizontal", "angular", "vertical", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "vertical",
    question: "In vertical milling machine the spindle is attached _______ to the work table.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["60°", "45°", "30°", "90°"],
    correctAnswer: "60°",
    question: "The included angle of a dead center is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["speed", "feed", "none of the above", "cutting speed"],
    correctAnswer: "feed",
    question: "An advance motion along the longitudinal axis of a twist drill is called:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium grains", "none of the above", "fine grains", "coarse grains"],
    correctAnswer: "fine grains",
    question: "Hardened steel parts have:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["coarse grain", "fine grain", "very fine grain", "medium grain"],
    correctAnswer: "medium grain",
    question: "As per Indian standard, the grain size 46 comes under the group:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["two", "one", "three or more", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "two",
    question: "In a straddle milling operation how many cutters are used to mill the work:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["have threads on one end", "inserted in plane hole", "require a nut", "none of the above "],
    correctAnswer: "none of the above ",
    question: "A stud is which:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["80°", "70°", "35°", "60°"],
    correctAnswer: "60°",
    question: "For general work the cutting angle of a cold flat chisel is ground at an angle of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it can resists more heat", "cutting speed can be increased", "it can keep the cutting point sharp", "all of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "A tipped tool is more useful than H.S.S. tool because:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it assists for quick melting and increasing the fluidity of solder", "it saves the part from oxidation", "all of the above", "it takes the molten metal on all surfaces"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "While soldering the flux is used because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["half center", "pipe center", "ball center", "female center"],
    correctAnswer: "pipe center",
    question: "Which center is used for supporting open end of pipes, shells, etc. while turning or thread cutting in a lathe:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["grooving", "facing", "angle cutting", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "The lathe compound is used for",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["surface speed too low", "too much longitudinal feed", "unnecessary support with tail stock center", "clamped length of tool too short"],
    correctAnswer: "too much longitudinal feed",
    question: "Which of the following conditions may cause error during knurling:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["52 HRC", "62 HRC", "45 HRC", "72 HRC"],
    correctAnswer: "62 HRC",
    question: "The approximate hardness of HSS and mill cutter is.                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["vitrified", "shellac", "rubber", "silicon"],
    correctAnswer: "vitrified",
    question: "Which kind of bond is commonly used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above", "fuel", "heat ", "oxygen"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "The out break of fire can be avoided by preventing:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["20:1", "30:1", "10:1", "40:1"],
    correctAnswer: "40:1",
    question: "In a standard worm dividing head the ration between the worm wheel and the worm is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["9 full rotation", "4 full rotation, 12 holes on the 27 hole circle", "5 full rotation, 2 holes on the 36 hole circle", "2 full rotation, 16 holes on the 47 hole circle"],
    correctAnswer: "4 full rotation, 12 holes on the 27 hole circle",
    question: "A polygon with 9 flats is to be milled using the indexing head. The indexing head transmission ratio is 40:1. Determine the number of crank rotation and mark the correct answer.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["all of the above", "width of face", "diameter of wheel", "bore size"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "The size of a grinding wheel is taken from:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["on the flank", "on the circumstances", "relieved cutters are not regrounded", "one the side faces"],
    correctAnswer: "on the flank",
    question: "Where the relieved cutters are reground:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["clamped length of tool too short", "too much longitudinal feed", "surface speed too low", "unnecessary support with tool stock center"],
    correctAnswer: "too much longitudinal feed",
    question: "Which of the following conditions may cause error during knurling?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["0.01 mm", "0.001 mm", "1.00 mm", "0.10 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "0.10 mm",
    question: "The value of one micron is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["1:10", "1:20", "20:1", "10:1"],
    correctAnswer: "10:1",
    question: "A usual ratio of soluble oil and water used in coolant is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["inside micrometer", "plug gauge", "vernier caliper", "dial test indicator"],
    correctAnswer: "inside micrometer",
    question: "For the accurate measurement of bores, the best instrument is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["decrease", "same", "none of the above", "increase"],
    correctAnswer: "increase",
    question: "For a given rpm. If the diameter if a twist drill increase, then the cutting speed will:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["silicon carbide", "corrundum", "combination of A and B", "aluminum oxide"],
    correctAnswer: "silicon carbide",
    question: "A grinding wheel has got the marking &amp;amp;#39;C&amp;amp;#39;, is made with the abrasive:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["form relief cutter", "all of the above", "plain milling cutter", "end mill cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "form relief cutter",
    question: "For gear cutting which cutter is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["G.I. Sheet", "lead", "Aluminum", "Cast Iron"],
    correctAnswer: "Aluminum",
    question: "Which is the lightest metal:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["column", "table", "arbor", "spindle"],
    correctAnswer: "arbor",
    question: "The over arm of a milling machine is used to support                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["turning", "grinding", "lapping", "honning"],
    correctAnswer: "honning",
    question: "In which method a bore is finished to a very closed tolerance:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["structure", "kind of abrasive", "hardness of bond", "grain size"],
    correctAnswer: "hardness of bond",
    question: "The grade of grinding wheel depends upon:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["meter per hour", "none of the above", "meter per second", "meter per minute"],
    correctAnswer: "meter per minute",
    question: "In a shaper the cutting speed (metric) is expressed in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["body", "tang", "point", "heel"],
    correctAnswer: "tang",
    question: "Which of the following file is not hardened:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["high carbon steel", "case hardened mild steel", "high speed steel", "alloy steel"],
    correctAnswer: "case hardened mild steel",
    question: "Fixture clamps are generally made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["opposite direction", "will not rotate", "none of the above", "same direction"],
    correctAnswer: "same direction",
    question: "When an external gear is meshed with an internal gear, the gears will rotate in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["height", "opposite side", "adjacent side", "hypotenuse"],
    correctAnswer: "hypotenuse",
    question: "Under sine principle the length of sine bar takes place of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above", "three or more", "two", "one"],
    correctAnswer: "two",
    question: "In a straddle milling operation how many cutters are used to mill the work:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["a make the outside diameter concentric with the bore", "none of the above", "make the sides of wheel parallel", "equalize the weight in every portion of the wheel"],
    correctAnswer: "equalize the weight in every portion of the wheel",
    question: "Balancing of grinding wheel is done to:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["above center", "off center ", "at the center", "below the center"],
    correctAnswer: "at the center",
    question: "When facing off a piece of material in the lathe chuck the bit must be set",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium duty", "none of the above", "heavy duty", "light duty"],
    correctAnswer: "heavy duty",
    question: "Planer type milling machine is built up for work of:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "10 degree ", "70 degree", "80 degree"],
    correctAnswer: "10 degree ",
    question: "If the clearance of a cutting edge is 5 degrees, the lip (wedge) angle in 75 degree the rake angle will be,",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "screw thread micrometer", "combi micrometer", "inside micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "inside micrometer",
    question: "Which micrometer is available with extension rods:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above ", "lower speed", "higher speed", "average speed"],
    correctAnswer: "higher speed",
    question: "In a hydraulic driven shaper the metal is removed at:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["wheel is hard", "grain size is too fine", "wheel speed is too fast", "A and B both"],
    correctAnswer: "A and B both",
    question: "One of the cause of grinding wheel glazing is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["&amp;amp;#39;Go&amp;amp;#39; Size", "none of the above", "&amp;amp;#39;Not Go&amp;amp;#39; Size", "A and B both"],
    correctAnswer: "&amp;amp;#39;Not Go&amp;amp;#39; Size",
    question: "In case of a limit plug gauge which size will not enter into the hole:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["A and B both", "neither A and B", "same direction", "opposite direction"],
    correctAnswer: "opposite direction",
    question: "In internal cylindrical grinding the grinding wheel and the work rotate in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["to control the size", "all of the above", "to finish the job to a fine degree of accuracy", "to get high quality of surface teeth"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "Lapping is done",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium", "soft", "none of the above", "hard"],
    correctAnswer: "medium",
    question: "As per Indian standard &amp;amp;#39;M&amp;amp;#39; grade wheel comes under the group:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["during up cut milling with a straight tooth cutter", "during face milling with a straight tooth cutter", "during down cut milling with a straight tooth cutter", "while using spiral tooth cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "during up cut milling with a straight tooth cutter",
    question: "Mark the milling method during which the formation of chatter marks is very likely.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["45°", "47.5°", "60°", "55°"],
    correctAnswer: "47.5°",
    question: "The angle of B.A. screw thread is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["plain milling cutter", "end mill cutter", "all of the above", "form relieve cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "form relieve cutter",
    question: "For gear cutting which cutter is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["straight", "right hand", "left hand", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "left hand",
    question: "Generally spiral fluted reamer has spirals of:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["column", "spindle", "table", "arbor"],
    correctAnswer: "arbor",
    question: "The over arm of a milling machine is used to support:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["in &amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; form", "parallel to each other", "A and B both", "neither A nor B"],
    correctAnswer: "in &amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; form",
    question: "The jaws of a leg vice are opened:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["on face plate", "in three jaw chuck", "on lathe mandrel", "between centers"],
    correctAnswer: "on lathe mandrel",
    question: "When outside diameter of a job is turned in relation to the internal hole, the job should be held:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the beginning of return stroke", "the middle of return stroke", "the beginning of cutting stroke", "the end of return stroke"],
    correctAnswer: "the end of return stroke",
    question: "The feed in the shaper takes place at:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["high carbon steel", "H.S.S.", "lead", "wood"],
    correctAnswer: "wood",
    question: "The clamping block to be used in a slotter to support the end of the strap is made of",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "changing its inclination", "changing the convexity of the cutting angle", "changing its weight"],
    correctAnswer: "changing its inclination",
    question: "In case of a flat scraper, the depth of the cut is verified by:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["hydraulic mechanism", "slotter link and gear mechanism", "whitworth mechanism", "slotter dist mechanism"],
    correctAnswer: "whitworth mechanism",
    question: "Which of the following quick return mechanism is most widely used in most of the slotters:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the blade have very sharp teeth", "the space is not sufficient to play the new blade in the old cut", "none of the above", "the blade is very costly"],
    correctAnswer: "the space is not sufficient to play the new blade in the old cut",
    question: "A new hacksaw blade should not be used in old cut because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["away from the center of crank disc", "at the center of crank", "none of the above", "towards the center of crank disc"],
    correctAnswer: "away from the center of crank disc",
    question: "Amount of automatic feed in shaper is increased by taking the crank pin:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["kind of bond", "kind of abrasive", "grain size", "structure"],
    correctAnswer: "structure",
    question: "A grinding wheel is marked as 51A 46L 5V 23, out of these 5 means:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["mm/stroke", "mm/revolution", "meter/minute", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "mm/stroke",
    question: "In a shaper the feed (metric) is usually expressed in:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it is specially designed by experts", "none of the above ", "it is easy for production", "it accomodates the handle and a wedge for preventing it from flying off"],
    correctAnswer: "it accomodates the handle and a wedge for preventing it from flying off",
    question: "The eye hole of a hammer head is made in oval shape and taper towards centre because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["none of the above", "chamois leather or lenen cloth", "brush", "cotton waste"],
    correctAnswer: "chamois leather or lenen cloth",
    question: "Which of the following is used to clean the gauge blocks before and after use:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["5 mm", "15 mm", "25 mm", "50 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "15 mm",
    question: "Shaper tool bit should not extend in tool holder beyond:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["semi-soft", "semi-hard", "hard", "soft"],
    correctAnswer: "hard",
    question: "The jaw of a standard vise is",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["at the end of return motion", "after each forward stroke", "during the cutting motion", "after each double stroke"],
    correctAnswer: "after each double stroke",
    question: "Where does the speed motion takes place in slotting machine?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cast steel", "tool steel", "high speed steel", "closed grain cast iron"],
    correctAnswer: "closed grain cast iron",
    question: "Angle plate is made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["62 HRC", "72 HRC", "45 HRC", "52 HRC"],
    correctAnswer: "62 HRC",
    question: "The approximate hardness of HSS end mill cutter is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["a cam", "an eccentric", "A and C", "a round stock"],
    correctAnswer: "A and C",
    question: "A universal chuck cannot be used to cut",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["actual and nominal", "minimum and maximum", "nominal and lower limit", "nominal and upper limit"],
    correctAnswer: "minimum and maximum",
    question: "Limit gauge is made to the ________ sizes of the work to be measured:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: [" ", "prevent the loading of wheel", "all of the above", "reduce the friction between the wheel face and the job"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "Grinding fluids are used to:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "screw thread micrometer", "digit micrometer", "depth micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "depth micrometer",
    question: "Which micrometer has no anvil:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["side milling cutters", "face milling cutters", "form cutters", "plain milling cutters"],
    correctAnswer: "side milling cutters",
    question: "The straddle milling is done by means of two:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["square", "knuckle", "acme", "buttress"],
    correctAnswer: "square",
    question: "In which screw thread the side = width of flat = width space = 0.5p",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["relief", "flutes", "threads", "diameter"],
    correctAnswer: "flutes",
    question: "Taps are resharpened by grindings:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["T = N/20", "T = 40/N", "T = 20/N", "T= N/40"],
    correctAnswer: "T = 40/N",
    question: "The formula to find out the number of turn of the crank for simple indexing is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["A and B both", "neither A and B", "upper limit of the shaft", "lower limit of the shaft"],
    correctAnswer: "A and B both",
    question: "&amp;amp;#39;Go&amp;amp;#39; Limit is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["materials of the slotter tool", "finish required", "material to be used", "all of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "In a slotter the cutting speed depends upon:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium duty", "none of the above", "light duty", "heavy duty"],
    correctAnswer: "heavy duty",
    question: "Planer type milling machine is built up for _____ work of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["tungsten", "nickel", "vanadium", "chromium"],
    correctAnswer: "tungsten",
    question: "Main alloying element in H.S.S. is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["18% Chromium and 8% Nickel", "18% Nickel and 8% Chromium", "18% Chromium and 8% Cobalt", "18% Tungsten and 8% Chromium"],
    correctAnswer: "18% Chromium and 8% Nickel",
    question: "&amp;amp;#39;18 - 8&amp;amp;#39; stainless steel means:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["10 mm", "100 mm", "1 mm", "4 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "100 mm",
    question: "If rpm = 200, feed per revolution = 0.05mm, then feed per minute will be:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["semi-circular milling cutter", "shell end mill", "plain milling cutter", "side milling cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "shell end mill",
    question: "Mark the cutter which works simultaneously with up cut and down cut process:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["corrundum", "emery", "silicon carbide", "aluminum carbide"],
    correctAnswer: "silicon carbide",
    question: "For grinding materials having low tensile strength which abrasive is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["4°", "6°", "1°", "2°"],
    correctAnswer: "1°",
    question: "In a standard dividing head 3 holes in 27 holes circles will be:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["3:1", "3:2", "2:3", "1:3"],
    correctAnswer: "3:2",
    question: "The standard ratio of cutting to return stroke in shaper is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["outside micrometer", "dial test indicator", "vernier caliper", "tube micrometer"],
    correctAnswer: "dial test indicator",
    question: "Concentricity of a outside diameter can be checked by:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["two housing", "one housing", "one table", "two tables"],
    correctAnswer: "two tables",
    question: "Divided table planer has:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["clamping arrangement", "tool guiding element", "all of the above ", "manufacturing conditions"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above ",
    question: "Successful designing of jigs and fixtures depend upon:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["thread plug gauge", "thread ring gauge", "plug gauge", "ring gauge"],
    correctAnswer: "thread plug gauge",
    question: "Which gauge is used to check the internal threads:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["one", "none of the above", "three or more", "two"],
    correctAnswer: "three or more",
    question: "In a slotter the table gets ______ different feeds:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["&amp;amp;#39;B&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;R&amp;amp;#39;", "&amp;amp;#39;E&amp;amp;#39;"],
    correctAnswer: "&amp;amp;#39;B&amp;amp;#39;",
    question: "The symbol conventionally used for resinoid bond is:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["speed is too fast", "speed is too low", "material cannot be done", "material is too hard"],
    correctAnswer: "speed is too fast",
    question: "When lathe tool bit burns, it means that the",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["the job will be out of round", "the job will be thrown out", "the job will not rotate", "the job will be oversized"],
    correctAnswer: "the job will be out of round",
    question: "What happens if the job is loosely fitted between centers in cylindrical grindings:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["cast iron", "tool steel", "brass", "mild steel"],
    correctAnswer: "tool steel",
    question: "Jig bushings are generally made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["form", "round nose", "&amp;amp;#39;V&amp;amp;#39; shaped", "gooseneck"],
    correctAnswer: "form",
    question: "For cutting gear teeth in a shaper, the ______ tool is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["45° only", "90° only", "any angle between 0° - 108", "90° and 45°"],
    correctAnswer: "90° and 45°",
    question: "The square head of a combination set is used for markings or checking the angles",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["horizontal", "angular", "vertical", "none of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "vertical",
    question: "In vertical milling machine the spindle is attached _______ to the work table.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["60°", "45°", "30°", "90°"],
    correctAnswer: "60°",
    question: "The included angle of a dead center is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["speed", "feed", "none of the above", "cutting speed"],
    correctAnswer: "feed",
    question: "An advance motion along the longitudinal axis of a twist drill is called:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["medium grains", "none of the above", "fine grains", "coarse grains"],
    correctAnswer: "fine grains",
    question: "Hardened steel parts have:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["coarse grain", "fine grain", "very fine grain", "medium grain"],
    correctAnswer: "medium grain",
    question: "As per Indian standard, the grain size 46 comes under the group:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["two", "one", "three or more", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "two",
    question: "In a straddle milling operation how many cutters are used to mill the work:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["have threads on one end", "inserted in plane hole", "require a nut", "none of the above "],
    correctAnswer: "none of the above ",
    question: "A stud is which:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["80°", "70°", "35°", "60°"],
    correctAnswer: "60°",
    question: "For general work the cutting angle of a cold flat chisel is ground at an angle of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it can resists more heat", "cutting speed can be increased", "it can keep the cutting point sharp", "all of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "A tipped tool is more useful than H.S.S. tool because:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["it assists for quick melting and increasing the fluidity of solder", "it saves the part from oxidation", "all of the above", "it takes the molten metal on all surfaces"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "While soldering the flux is used because:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["half center", "pipe center", "ball center", "female center"],
    correctAnswer: "pipe center",
    question: "Which center is used for supporting open end of pipes, shells, etc. while turning or thread cutting in a lathe:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["grooving", "facing", "angle cutting", "any of the above"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "The lathe compound is used for",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["surface speed too low", "too much longitudinal feed", "unnecessary support with tail stock center", "clamped length of tool too short"],
    correctAnswer: "too much longitudinal feed",
    question: "Which of the following conditions may cause error during knurling:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["52 HRC", "62 HRC", "45 HRC", "72 HRC"],
    correctAnswer: "62 HRC",
    question: "The approximate hardness of HSS and mill cutter is.                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["vitrified", "shellac", "rubber", "silicon"],
    correctAnswer: "vitrified",
    question: "Which kind of bond is commonly used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above", "fuel", "heat ", "oxygen"],
    correctAnswer: "any of the above",
    question: "The out break of fire can be avoided by preventing:                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["20:1", "30:1", "10:1", "40:1"],
    correctAnswer: "40:1",
    question: "In a standard worm dividing head the ration between the worm wheel and the worm is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["9 full rotation", "4 full rotation, 12 holes on the 27 hole circle", "5 full rotation, 2 holes on the 36 hole circle", "2 full rotation, 16 holes on the 47 hole circle"],
    correctAnswer: "4 full rotation, 12 holes on the 27 hole circle",
    question: "A polygon with 9 flats is to be milled using the indexing head. The indexing head transmission ratio is 40:1. Determine the number of crank rotation and mark the correct answer.",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["all of the above", "width of face", "diameter of wheel", "bore size"],
    correctAnswer: "all of the above",
    question: "The size of a grinding wheel is taken from:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["on the flank", "on the circumstances", "relieved cutters are not regrounded ", "one the side faces"],
    correctAnswer: "on the flank",
    question: "Where the relieved cutters are reground:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["clamped length of tool too short", "too much longitudinal feed", "surface speed too low", "unnecessary support with tool stock center"],
    correctAnswer: "too much longitudinal feed",
    question: "Which of the following conditions may cause error during knurling?",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["0.01 mm", "0.001 mm", "1.00 mm", "0.10 mm"],
    correctAnswer: "0.10 mm",
    question: "The value of one micron is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["1:10", "1:20", "20:1", "10:1"],
    correctAnswer: "10:1",
    question: "A usual ratio of soluble oil and water used in coolant is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["inside micrometer", "plug gauge", "vernier caliper", "dial test indicator"],
    correctAnswer: "inside micrometer",
    question: "For the accurate measurement of bores, the best instrument is:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["decrease", "same", "none of the above", "increase"],
    correctAnswer: "increase",
    question: "For a given rpm. If the diameter if a twist drill increase, then the cutting speed will:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["silicon carbide", "corrundum", "combination of A and B", "aluminum oxide"],
    correctAnswer: "silicon carbide",
    question: "A grinding wheel has got the marking &amp;amp;#39;C&amp;amp;#39;, is made with the abrasive:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["form relief cutter", "all of the above", "plain milling cutter", "end mill cutter"],
    correctAnswer: "form relief cutter",
    question: "For gear cutting which cutter is used:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["G.I. Sheet", "lead", "Aluminum", "Cast Iron"],
    correctAnswer: "Aluminum",
    question: "Which is the lightest metal:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["column", "table", "arbor", "spindle"],
    correctAnswer: "arbor",
    question: "The over arm of a milling machine is used to support                                    ",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["turning", "grinding", "lapping", "honning"],
    correctAnswer: "honning",
    question: "In which method a bore is finished to a very closed tolerance:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["structure", "kind of abrasive", "hardness of bond", "grain size"],
    correctAnswer: "hardness of bond",
    question: "The grade of grinding wheel depends upon:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["meter per hour", "none of the above", "meter per second", "meter per minute"],
    correctAnswer: "meter per minute",
    question: "In a shaper the cutting speed (metric) is expressed in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["body", "tang", "point", "heel"],
    correctAnswer: "tang",
    question: "Which of the following file is not hardened:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["high carbon steel", "case hardened mild steel", "high speed steel", "alloy steel"],
    correctAnswer: "case hardened mild steel",
    question: "Fixture clamps are generally made of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["opposite direction", "will not rotate", "none of the above", "same direction"],
    correctAnswer: "same direction",
    question: "When an external gear is meshed with an internal gear, the gears will rotate in:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["height", "opposite side", "adjacent side", "hypotenuse"],
    correctAnswer: "hypotenuse",
    question: "Under sine principle the length of sine bar takes place of:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
  {
    choices: ["any of the above", "three or more", "two", "one"],
    correctAnswer: "two",
    question: "In a straddle milling operation how many cutters are used to mill the work:",
    topic: "NA"
  },
]